Okay, so let's talk about the PIMBOC guide
processes as it relates
to resource management.
And of course, remember, this is talking
about PIMBock Guide, PIMBORTION 6.
Now, so in PIMBoc then,
in PIMBF version 6, there
are six processes altogether
in resource management.
And this is one of the areas where PMI
have really expanded.
Right, so for the new exam, for the 2021
ECO, right?
like the new exam content outline,
they've really, really expanded this area.
So this area, a lot of it refers to
leadership, right, the leadership section
or the people management section,
rather the people domain section.
And so this is the area they've really,
really expanded.
Now, resource management refers to both
physical resources as well as team
resources, Physical resources refers to
things like equipment, supplies,
raw materials, facilities, and then team
resources refers to your team,
right, human resources.
So essentially, physical resources are
anything but humans, right?
Resource management really refers to both,
right, equipment supplies, raw materials.
These are all resources on your project,
as well as team members as well.
Now, for the new exam,
though, much of resource
management really is focused on the team.
Now, that doesn't mean they're
not focused on, or that doesn't
mean they're not referring
to physical resources at all.
No, no, no.
You still refer, I mean, you know,
we still have the physical resources.
We still talk about equipment and raw
materials and so and so forth.
But because, you know, much of the exam is
the people domain and people domain then.
refers to leadership and leadership of
your team members, stakeholders,
and, you know, much of that is resources
here.
So anyway, these are the processes then,
the six processes that fall under
planning, executing and monitoring,
controlling, respectively.
First process, plan resource management,
right?
Just like any, just like all of the
knowledge areas in Pinbox six,
in the Pinbox six guide, the very first
process in each knowledge area is plan
something management and the output is
that management plan, right?
So the output of plan resource management
is the resource management plan.
And resource management
plan then is documenting how, you
know, we're going to identify
resources and so and so forth.
Separate video on that.
Now, along with that then, there's also
another output, right, another,
or what, you know, what PMI
calls the output, which is really
just an artifact, it's just a
document that we're creating.
So another output is something called the
team charter.
The team charter then is
documenting the team agreement
and the do's and don'ts of
the team and that kind of thing.
Again, we're covering all of this in a
separate video.
One of the other processes then in
planning is estimate activity resources.
So basically for each
activity, what equipment
supplies, labor or materials are required.
And then the output, if you like, of that
process was the activity
resource estimate.
That's the way it was called.
At least the main output.
And executing, we have acquire resources.
So basically, in planning, you're planning
what resources we need.
In acquire resources, we're actually
physically going out and collecting,
physically going out and getting those
resources, whether it's internal to the
organization or external to the
organization.
If it's external to the organization,
then that refers to procurement.
which again is a completely
separate knowledge area,
which we're going to cover
in a separate set of videos.
But acquire resources basically means,
you know, like basically getting your raw
materials, physically getting your
equipment, ordering your equipment or
basically booking your
equipment if it's internal, scheduling
your equipment and raw
materials and so and so forth.
And then plus team members as well,
identifying team members, adding a name to
a role, That's really what Acquire
Resources refers to.
And then you have developed team and
managed team, right?
So these two processes then are the areas
that PMI have really expanded.
And so, you know, we have many videos on
leadership.
And then you have control resources.
And control resources
then refers to monitoring,
controlling, all of the
different resources.
Now, for PMI's purposes, though,
for PinBox, six guide purposes.
Control resources
specifically refer to monitoring
and controlling physical resources, right?
So equipment, supplies, raw materials,
facilities, machines.
These are all physical resources.
So control resources always referred to
monitoring and controlling
the physical resources.
Okay.
So these were the six processes then that
are part of the PIMBOC guide.
right, the six PIMBOT guide processes of
resource management.